Shakeel Ansari

Associate Director @ UBS India

ShakeelAnsari63@gmail.com







) +91 963 206 5955

ROLES

- Associate Director @ UBS
- Senior Data Engineer @Teradata
- DevOps and DataEngineer @ IBM
- > Data Specialist @ IBM

SKILLS

- > Python
- > Bash / Shell Script
- > PySpark
- > Azure
- > AWS
- > Teradata
- > Hadoop / HDFS
- > Hive
- > Data Warehouse
- > Sqoop
- > Informatica Powercenter
- > Oracle Database
- > Oracle Data Integrator
- › Docker
- → Git
- > Jenkins
- > MongoDB
- > Mainframe

INDUSTRIES

- > Healthcare
- > Finance

CERTIFICATIONS

- Teradata CertifiedProfessional
- AWS Certified Developer
 Associate
- > Azure Fundamentals

SUMMARY

A consultant who is adept at solution design, data engineering, system programming and DevOps.

Packaged with proficiency in Agile methods and a hunger for challenges, I am the specialist who every organization seeks but rarely succeeds to find and hire.

Here is a brief of my credentials and a peek into my evolution into a technologist who can write the design specifications, build application, code to specs and then put it live on a continuous delivery pipeline.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UBS INDIA

Associate Director

Nov 2022 - Present

- Worked on Decommissioning Legacy On-Premise Hadoop and Aster Platforms and migrating Data Feeds to Teradata
- > Built a generic data pipeline for data migration from On-Premise Teradata Database to Amazon S3
- > Built automated security alerts with process to monitor database logs and alert for security breaches

TERADATA INDIA PVT. LTD.

Senior Data Engineer

Feb 2020 - Nov 2022

- Worked on Decommissioning Legacy On-Premise Hadoop and Aster
 Platforms and migrating Data Feeds to Teradata
- Built a generic data pipeline for data migration from On-Premise
 Teradata Database to Amazon S3
- > Built automated reports delivery to business on critical business processes

IBM AUSTRALIA PTY. LTD.

DevOps and Data Engineer

May 2016 - Feb 2020

- Reduced manual efforts of operations team by automation of monitoring critical batch progress, send email alerts on Success / Failure and easy to use Batch progress dashboard
- Migrated 100+ production processes to new and low-cost server within a period of 1 month
- Reduced development effort from 5 days to 2 hours by automated
 Python based code build to remediate BMIT (Business Managed IT)
 SAS Scripts to production code

EDUCATION

Nagpur University 2008 - 2012

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Technology)

Aggregate: 74.07%

SOCIAL LINKS



https://linkedin.com/in/shak eelansari63

GitHub -

https://github.com/shakeela nsari63

☆ Credly -

https://www.credly.com/use rs/shakeelansari63

- Designed and developed custom process control framework to simplify development and support of Teradata data ingestion processes
- Removed technical debt by consolidating CI/CD (Build and Deployment) infrastructure and developing a single Jenkins pipeline for multiple platform components
- > 50% reduction in operational incidents through multiple initiatives as onshore Tech Lead

IBM INDIA PVT. LTD.

Data Specialist

Nov 2012 – May 2016

- > Built data pipelines for ingesting Claims, Membership and Customer Risk scores data from Transactional source to Teradata Data warehouse for US Healthcare client.
- Reduced effort in deployment planning by more than 30% by automating code consistency check and reporting across Development, Test and Production environments
- Developed Android App for operational health dashboard and mobile notification
- Reduced Development efforts by developing Generic Data Copy
 Procedure to copy data from old table to table with new definition

RECOGNITIONS

- > Recognised as IBM Subject Matter Expert on Big Data
- Invited as Guest Speaker on Big Data at Federation University Ballarat, Australia
- > Twice recipient of Orion IBM Global Business Services award for Dedication to Client Success
- Handpicked as IBM team's only representative on NAB Design Community of Practice

HOBBY PROJECTS

SQLYSER

SQLyser is an SQL Analyzer tool written in Python to decode an SQL Statement and build lineage from SQL Scripts

GitHub Project: https://github.com/shakeelansari63/sqlyser

COWIN SLOTS

COWIN Slots is a frontend to Indian Government's Public API which can be used to locate Covid Vaccine slots and download Vaccination Certificate

GitHub Project: https://github.com/shakeelansari63/cowin-slots